谁将接替埃米利亚诺·马丁内斯？
Who will succeed Emiliano Martinez?
这是五名决赛入围者。
Here are the five finalists.
矢志奖杯的获得者，由代表国际足联排名前 50 名国家的 50 名记者选出
The winner of the Yashii Trophy, chosen by fifty journalists representing the top fifty countries in the FIFA rankings
El ganador del Yashii Trophy, elegido por cincuenta periodistas representando a los top cincuenta países en los ranking FIFA
洛塔罗，上帝不是你的。
Lotharo, God is not yours.
Lotharo, Dios no es tuyo.
获胜者是埃米利亚诺·马丁内斯。
The winner is Emiliano Martínez.
El ganador es Emiliano Martínez.
埃米利亚诺.
Emiliano.
又是你吗？
You again?
¿Tú de nuevo?
请先说几句话。
A few first words please.
Unos primeros palabras por favor.
很荣幸再次来到这里。
It's an honor to be here again.
Es un honor volver a estar acá.
我一直很感激自己在决赛中为队友进球。
I have always been grateful for scoring the goal in the final for my teammate.
Siempre me ha agradecido meter el gol en la final mi compañero de la selección.
阿拉斯顿维拉，今天我很高兴能和看到我的两位守门员教练在一起......
Alastón Vila, today I have the pleasure of being with the two goalkeeper coaches of mine who see me...
Alastón Vila, hoy tengo el placer de estar con los dos entrenadores arqueros míos que me ven...
他每天都知道我对继续进步的要求有多么高。
Every day he knows how demanding I am to continue improving.
Todos los días sabe lo exigente que soy al seguir mejorando.
我总是来自一个小地方，我总是记得它，这就是一直激励我的东西。
I always come from a small place and I always remember it and that is what always motivates me.
Vengo siempre de un lugar chico y siempre lo recuerdo y eso es lo que me motiva siempre.
继续想要成长，继续痴迷于进步，继续实现团队目标，这对我来说是……
to continue wanting to grow, to continue obsessed with improving, with achieving group things, which for me is...
a seguir queriendo crecer, a seguir obsesionado con mejorar, con conseguir cosas grupales que para mí es...
个人总是追随群体。
Individuals always come after the group.
Los individuos siempre vienen después de lo grupal.
因此，我们始终感谢所有人，并非常感谢在决赛中进球的一切。
So we are always grateful to everyone and thank you well to everything that scored the goal in the final.
Así que agradecidos a todos siempre y gracias bueno a todo lo que metió el gol en la final.
恭喜，埃米利亚诺！
Congratulations, Emiliano!
¡Felicidades, Emiliano!
多么令人难以置信的一年啊！
What an incredible year!
¡Qué año increíble!
让我们看看他是如何成为...
Let's see how he became the...
Vamos a ver cómo se convirtió en el...
和可能的。
and possible.
为什么不现在就经历它，经历它的痛苦呢？
Why not go through it now, with its misery?
¿Por qué no pasarlo ahora, con su miseria?
马丁内斯起跳。
Martínez makes the jump.
Martínez hace el salto.
另一位 Ligo 获奖者是埃米利亚诺·马丁内斯 (Emiliano Martínez)。
Another Ligo winner is Emiliano Martínez.
Otro ganador del Ligo es Emiliano Martínez.
你连续赢得这个奖杯。
You win this trophy back to back.
这在历史上还是第一次。
This is the first time in history.
这对你来说是巨大的。
This is huge for you.
是的，确实，这对我来说意义重大。
Yes, really, it's huge for me.
Sí, de verdad, es enorme para mí.
我从小就梦想着为国家队踢比赛。
I have always dreamt of playing a game for the national team and coming from such a young age.
Siempre he dreamt de jugar un juego para el equipo nacional y venir de tan joven.
到英国，尝试走我的路。
to England, trying to walk my way.
a Inglaterra, intentando caminar mi camino.
阿森纳维拉的球队和国家队。
Arsene Vila's team and the national team.
El equipo de Arsene Vila y el equipo nacional.
对我来说，这是一种荣幸，再次工作是我从未想到过的，真的。
For me it was an honor, working again is something I never expected, really.
Para mí fue un honor, volver a trabajar es algo que nunca esperaba, de verdad.
我今天很荣幸来到这里。
I am very proud to be here today.
Estoy muy orgulloso de estar aquí hoy.
这一切都要感谢我的家人和朋友。
All thanks to my family and my friends.
Todo gracias a mi familia y a mis amigos.
你是一个非常特别的人。
You are a very special person.
Eres una persona muy especial.
我想我们现在都知道了。
I think we all know that now.
Creo que todos lo sabemos ahora.
你是一个爱作秀的人，你喜欢激怒你的对手。
You are a kind of showman, you like to provoke your opponents.
Usted es un tipo de showman, le gusta provocar a sus oponentes.
他喜欢溶解它们。
He likes to dissolve them.
Le gusta disolverlos.
我们永远不知道你的下一步行动会是什么。
We never know what your next move will be.
Nunca sabemos cuál será vuestro próximo movimiento.
这是你的特殊风格吗？
Is that your special touch?
¿Es ese su toque especial?
不。
No.
这不是我的专长。
It's not my specialty.
No es mi especialidad.
有时候当你遇到困难时...
Sometimes when you're in a pinch...
A veces, cuando estás en la pizca...
他的行为方式就是他想要赢得比赛的方式。
He behaves the way he wants to win the game.
Se comporta de la manera que quiere ganar la partida.
在泳池里，我是一个男人，我是一个自豪的男人。
From the pool, I'm a guy, I'm a proud man.
De la piscina, soy un tío, soy un hombre orgulloso.
我是一个丈夫、一个兄弟、一个儿子。
I am a husband, a brother, a son.
Soy un marido, un hermano, un hijo.
我想尽我所能帮助我的国家队。
I want to do everything I can to help my national team.
Quiero hacer todo lo que puedo para ayudar a mi equipo nacional.
在我的俱乐部阿斯顿维拉，我们正在做一些令人难以置信的事情。
At my club, which is Aston Villa, we are doing something incredible.
en mi club, que es Aston Villa, estamos haciendo algo increíble.
在俱乐部，我们前进，我们与国家队一起背靠背，这对我来说才是最重要的。
At the club, we go forward, we go back to back with the national team and that's all that matters to me.
en el club, vamos adelante, vamos de vuelta a vuelta con el equipo nacional y eso es todo lo que me importa.
但有时会被视为太多，对吧？
But sometimes it can be seen as too much, right?
Pero a veces se puede ver como demasiado, ¿verdad?
这就是阿根廷人的看法。
That's the way Argentines see it.
Esa es la forma de verlo para los argentinos.
完美，完美。
Perfect, perfect.
Perfecto, perfecto.
你必须道歉，你必须道歉。
You have to apolicate, you have to apolicate.
Ustedes tienen que apoligar, tienen que apoligar.
你现在是世界上最好的得分手，被一轮又一轮地投票。
You are the best scorer in the world right now, being voted round after round.
Usted es el mejor goleador del mundo en este momento, siendo elegido de vuelta a vuelta.
冠军，美洲杯冠军，也就是说，你现在是最好的。
champion, winner of the Copa América, that is, you are the best now.
campeón, ganador de Copa América, es decir, tú eres el mejor ahora.
不，公平地说，我不认为 Masao 是最好的。
No, to be fair, I don't see Masao as the best.
No, para ser justo, no veo a Masao como el mejor.
我今天看到了很多好目标。
There are so many good goals that I see today.
Hay tantos buenos goles que veo hoy.
我看到一周过去，一周过去。
I see a week in, a week out.
que veo una semana en, una semana fuera.
就像我说的，我只关心团队。
Like I said, I only care about the group.
Como dije, solo me importa el grupo.
与国家队，与阿斯顿维拉。
with the national team, with Aston Villa.
con el equipo nacional, con Aston Villa.
专注于我自己。
Focus on myself.
Focos en mí mismo.
显然，我的球员比我更多。
Obviously, my players are more than me.
Obviamente, mis jugadores son más que yo.
我每天与哈维和马丁一起做的工作帮助我进步。
The work I do every day with Javi and Martín helps me improve.
El trabajo que hago cada día con Javi y Martín me ayuda a mejorar.
卢塔，我们想知道埃米利亚诺在赛鸽之外或在禁区内的表现如何。
Louta, we want to know how Emiliano is doing outside of the pigeon or in the box.
Louta, queremos saber cómo está Emiliano fuera del pichón o en la caja.
你每天都会看到它。
You see it every day.
Lo ves todos los días.
埃米利亚诺对我们来说是一个特别的人，因为......
Emiliano for us is a special person because...
Emiliano para nosotros es una persona especial porque...
首先，他是一个胜利者，这一点很重要。
He is a winner, first of all, and this is important.
Es ganador, primera cosa, y esto es importante.
在一个团队内，然后...
within a team, then...
dentro de un equipo, después...
帮助年轻人，帮助男孩。
Help the younger ones, help the boys.
Ayuda a los más jóvenes, ayuda a los chicos.
他们来国家队和我们一起训练，之后我只能说一些话。
They come to train with us in the national team and afterwards I can only speak words.
que vienen a entrenar con nosotros en la selección y después puedo hablar solo palabras.
对他很美丽，因为他是一个伟大的人。
beautiful towards him because he is a great person.
bonitas hacia él porque es una gran persona.
正如我之前所说，也许他所做的一切都是因为他想赢，而且仅此而已。
As I said before, maybe everything he does he does because he wants to win and it doesn't go beyond that.
como dije antes, quizá todo lo que hace lo hace porque él quiere ganar y no va más allá de eso.
这些都是善意的话。
Those are kind words.
Esas son palabras amables.
伟大的。
Great.
劳塔罗，如果你必须对埃米利亚诺罚十个点球的话。
Lautaro, if you had to take ten penalty shots against Emiliano.
当然是专家。
The specialist, of course.
El especialista, por supuesto.
你认为你会有多少钱？
How much do you think you would have?
¿Cuánto crees que tendrías?
不要说谎。
Don't lie.
No mientas.
我不知道，这非常困难。
I don't know, it's very difficult.
No sé, es muy difícil.
还有一些。
Some more.
Un poco más.
但这非常困难，非常困难，因为首先它很大，其次......
but it is very difficult, it is very difficult because first it is big and second...
pero es muy difícil, es muy difícil porque primero es grande y segundo...
等到最后一件事，看了很多。
Wait until the last thing, look a lot.
Espera hasta lo último, mira mucho.
也许是 9、10。
Maybe 9, 10.
Tal vez 9, 10.
你的状态很好吧？
You're in good shape, huh?
Estás en buena forma, ¿eh?
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
非常感谢你们，女士们、先生们。
Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen.
Muchas gracias, señoras y señores.
现在，本周的获胜者是埃米利亚诺·马丁内斯。
And now, this week's winner, Emiliano Martinez.
Y ahora, el ganador de esta semana, Emiliano Martinez.
现在是时候揭晓法国足球女子金球奖第 7 名到第 5 名的获胜者是谁了。
Now it's time to reveal who won from 7th to 5th place in the women's ballon d'or France Fouball.
Ahora es tiempo de revelar quién ganó desde el 7º a el 5º lugar en el women's ballon d'or France Fouball.